<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tips and tricks on Jovche Mitrejchevski</title>
    <link>https://jovmit.io/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tips and tricks on Jovche Mitrejchevski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 11:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jovmit.io/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Studio/IntelliJ Idea side by side working setup</title>
      <link>https://jovmit.io/tips/android-studio-side-by-side-editor-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jovmit.io/tips/android-studio-side-by-side-editor-setup/</guid>
      <description>The way I prefer to work when I use Android Studio or IntelliJ Idea is splitting the production code and the related tests side-by-side. In this article I&amp;rsquo;d like to describe the setup and the shortcuts I use, so someone might find it useful as well.
The side-by-side setup (vertical editor splitting) Side by side editor
 We aim to use keyboard shortcuts for fast split and navigation instead of using mouse/trackpad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add custom live templates in Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://jovmit.io/tips/add-custom-templates-in-as/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 14:15:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jovmit.io/tips/add-custom-templates-in-as/</guid>
      <description>What is a custom live template In Android Studio, there is a concept of inserting a block of any textual content as a template wherever it is required, just by typing a keyword. By using live templates, we can insert frequently-used constructions into our code.
How is this going to be helpful? Live templates are super handy to boost our speed while writing code. Overtime we use the same or similar constructions in our code like loops, conditions, declarations and even whole class templates (think of for example RecyclerView.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>